Finding Aid for the Recordings of Evenings for New Music, 1964-1980
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Service copy compact discs reformatted from reel to reel tapes, 1964-1980, I.; CD 1-139
  - Evenings for New Music Concert 23, November 6, 1966, 1 compact disc; Transferred from: Reel 33 Preservation copy on DVD 14 Performed at Albright-Knox Art Gallery (Box 1, Cd 20)
    Performers: Shaul Ben Meir, flute; Paul Zonn, clarinet; Charles Haupt, violin; Robert Martin, violoncello; Richard Dufallo, conductor
    Duration: 5:04
    Work number: ENM023-05
    Amacher, Maryanne
    Adjacencies from Audjoins Suite (1965)
    Performers: Edward Burnham, Jan Williams, percussion
    Duration: 12:48
    Work number: ENM023-06
    Wuorinen, Charles
    Chamber concerto for cello and ten players (1963)
    Performers: Robert Martin, violoncello; Ensemble
    Duration: 17:35
  - Evenings for New Music Concert 25, December 17, 1966, 2 compact discs; Transferred from: Reel 34 Preservation copy on DVD 15 Performed at Albright-Knox Art Gallery (Box 1, Cd 21-22)
    Work number: ENM025-01
    Chávez, Carlos, 1899-1978
    Invention no. 2 for violin, viola, and cello (1966)
    Performers: Charles Haupt, violin; Jean Dupouy, viola; Robert Martin, violoncello
    Duration: 9:53
    Work number: ENM025-02
    Zonn, Paul Martin, 1938-2000
    Sonata for solo viola (1964)
    Performers: Jean Dupouy, viola
    Duration: 7:45
    Work number: ENM025-03
    Martirano, Salvatore
    Ballad (1966)
    Performers: Anne Graff, alto; Shaul Ben Meir, flute; Andrew White III, tenor saxophone; Fred Halt, trombone; Edward Burnham, Jan Williams, percussion; Jean Dupouy, viola; Makoto Michii, bass
    Duration: 11:55
    Work number: ENM025-04
    Castiglioni, Niccolò
    Canzoni (1966)
    Performers: Taeko Fujii, soprano; Shaul Ben Meir, flute; Andrew White III, oboe; Edward Burnham, Jan Williams, percussion; Carlos Roqué Alsina, piano; Cornelius Cardew, electronic organ; Richard Dufallo, conductor
    Duration: 16:53
    Work number: ENM025-05
    Cardew, Cornelius
    Treatise, Fragment American Pages (1966)
    Duration: 18:04
  - Evenings for New Music Concert 27, February 12, 1967, 1 compact disc; Transferred from: Reel 35-Reel 36 Preservation copy on DVD 16 Performed at Albright-Knox Art Gallery (Box 1, Cd 23)
    Work number: ENM027-01
    Sydeman, William, 1928-
    Duo for violin and piano (1963)
    Performers: Charles Haupt, violin; William Kothe, piano
    Duration: 19:57
    Work number: ENM027-02
    Powell, Mel
    Two prayer settings (1962)
    Performers: Warren Hoffer, tenor; Andrew White III, oboe; S. Lee Larrison, violin; Jean Dupouy, viola; Robert Martin, violoncello
    Duration: 4:53
    Work number: ENM027-03
    Roqué Alsina, Carlos, 1941-
    Funktionen, op. 14 (1965)
    Performers: Shaul Ben Meir, flute; Paul Zonn, clarinet; Darlene Reynard, bassoon; Frank Collura, trumpet; Edward Burnham, Jan Williams, percussion; Cornelius Cardew, piano; Charles Haupt, violin; Robert Martin, violoncello; Carlos Roqué Alsina, conductor
    Duration: 15:49
    Work number: ENM027-04
    Boulez, Pierre, 1925-
    Sonata, piano, no. 3. Format II Trope (1957-61)
    Performers: Carlos Roqué Alsina, piano
    Work number: ENM027-05
    Circles (1960)
    Performers: Anne Graff, alto; Edward Burnham, Jan Williams, percussion; Suzanne Thomas, harp
    Duration: 19:59
  - Evenings for New Music Concert 29, March 19, 1967, 1 compact disc; Transferred from: Reel 37-Reel 38 Preservation copy on DVD 17 Performed at Albright-Knox Art Gallery (Box 1, Cd 24)
    Work number: ENM029-01
    Smit, Leo, 1921-1999
    Academic graffiti (1962/63)
    Performers: Anne Graff, alto; Paul Zonn, clarinet; Edward Burnham, percussion; Cornelius Cardew, piano; Robert Martin, violoncello
    Duration: 5:56
    Work number: ENM029-02
    Wolpe, Stefan
    Piece for two instrumental units (1962)
    Performers: Shaul Ben Meir, flute; Andrew White III, oboe; Jan Williams, percussion, Cornelius Cardew, piano; Klaus von Wrochem, violin; Robert Martin, violoncello; Makoto Michii, bass; Richard Dufallo, conductor
    Duration: 13:12
    Work number: ENM029-03
    Gerhard, Roberto, 1896-1970
    Concert for eight (1965)
    Performers: Shaul Ben Meir, flute; Paul Zonn, clarinet; Edward Burnham, percussion; Cornelius Cardew, piano, Tony Mergel, accordion; Oswald Rantucci, mandolin; Nevel Barnes, guitar; Makoto Michii, bass; Richard Dufallo, conductor
    Duration: 11:18
    Work number: ENM029-04
    Wrochem, Klaus von
    Stücke (1966)
    Performers: Robert Sterling Beckwith, speaker; Anne Graff, alto; Warren Hoffer, tenor; Andrew White III, saxophone; William Penn, trumpet; Edward Burnham, Jan Williams, percussion; Carlos Roqué Alsina, gong; Cornelius Cardew, pneumatic drill; Charles Haupt, Klaus von Wrochem, violins; Jean Dupouy, viola; Robert Martin, violoncello; Makoto Michii, bass
    Duration: 30:27
  - Evenings for New Music Concert 31, April 29, 1967, 2 compact discs; Transferred from: Reel 39-Reel 40 Preservation copy on DVD 18 Performed at Albright-Knox Art Gallery (Box 1, Cd 25-26)
    Work number: ENM031-01
    Syverud, Stephen L. (Stephen Luther), 1938-
    Axis (1966)
    Performers: Shaul Ben Meir, flute; Andrew White III, oboe; Paul Zonn, clarinet; Edward Burnham, percussion; Robert Martin, violoncello; Jan Williams, conductor
    Duration: 6:36
    Work number: ENM031-02
    Two pieces for kettledrums (1966)
    Duration: 5:00
    Work number: ENM031-03
    Sonata, violoncello-piano (1948)
    Performers: Robert Martin, violoncello; Carlos Roqué Alsina, piano
    Duration: 21:17
    Work number: ENM031-04
    Albright, William
    Tic (1967)
    Performers: Andrew White III, alto saxophone; Edward Burnham, Jan Williams, percussion; electronic tape
    Duration: 12:25
    Work number: ENM031-05
    Stockhausen, Karlheinz, 1928-
    Plus minus (1962)
    Performers: Edward Burnham, percussion; Cornelius Cardew, piano, electronic organ
    Duration: 31:26
  - Evenings for New Music Concert 33, November 5, 1967, 2 compact discs; Transferred from: Reel 41-Reel 43 Preservation copy on DVD 19 Performed at Albright-Knox Art Gallery (Box 1, Cd 27-28)
    Work number: ENM033-01
    Nono, Luigi
    Canti per 13 (1955)
    Performers: David Shostac, flute; Lawrence Singer, oboe; Jerry Kirkbride, clarinet; Edward Yadzinski, bass clarinet; Darlene Reynard, bassoon; William Lane, horn; Jon Hassell, trumpet; Stuart Dempster, trombone; Donald Downs, violin; David Rosenboom, viola; Robert Martin, violoncello; Makoto Michii, bass; Harley Gaber, soprano saxophone; Lukas Foss, conductor
    Work number: ENM033-02
    Krenek, Ernst, 1900-1991
    Five pieces for trombone and piano (1967)
    Performers: Stuart Dempster, trombone; Carlos Roqué Alsina, piano
    Duration: 9:28
    Work number: ENM033-03
    Singer, Lawrence
    Concertazioni per ghitarra (1966)
    Performers: Jonathan Marcus, guitar; Lawrence Singer, oboe; Jesse Levine, viola; Robert Martin, violoncello; Edward Burnham, percussion
    Duration: 10:05
    Work number: ENM033-04
    Borup-Jørgensen, Axel, 1924-
    Aria per alto e strumenti (1967)
    Performers: Merete Bekkelund, mezzo-soprano; Jan Williams, percussion; Jonathan Marcus, guitar; Charles Haupt, violin; Jesse Levine, viola
    Duration: 10:26
    Work number: ENM033-05
    Johnston, Ben
    Knocking piece (1963)
    Duration: 6:59
    Work number: ENM033-06
    Wilson, Donald M., 1937-
    Seventeen views for violin and narrator (1966-67)
    Performers: Miriam Abramowitsch, narrator; Charles Haupt, violin
    Duration: 9:25
    Work number: ENM033-07
    Oliveros, Pauline, 1932-
    Theater piece for trombone player and tape (1966)
    Performers: Stuart Dempster, trombone; Elizabeth Harris, choreographer
    Duration: 15:35
  - Evenings for New Music Concert 35, December 16, 1967, 1 compact disc; Transferred from: Reel 44-Reel 46 Preservation copy on DVD 20 Performed at Albright-Knox Art Gallery (Box 1, Cd 29)
    Work number: ENM035-01
    Octet, wind (1952)
    Performers: David Shostac, flute; Jerry Kirkbride, clarinet; Nelson Dayton, Darlene Reynard, bassoons; Frank Collura, Jon Hassell, trumpets; Richard Myers, Stuart Dempster, trombones; Lukas Foss, conductor
    Duration: 14:37
    Work number: ENM035-02
    Gaber, Harley, 1943-
    Voce II (1964-65)
    Performers: Miriam Abramowitsch, soprano; David Shostac, flute; Jan Williams, percussion
    Duration: 9:55
    Work number: ENM035-03
    Rosenboom, David
    Then we wound through an aura of golden yellow gauze (1967)
    Performers: Miriam Abramowitsch, soprano; Merete Bekkelund, mezzo-soprano; David Shostac, flute; Stuart Dempster, trombone; Edward Burnham, percussion; David Rosenboom, harpsichord; Jonathan Marcus, guitar
    Duration: 24:15
    Work number: ENM035-04
    Maderna, Bruno
    Serenata no. 2 per 11 instrumenti (1957)
    Performers: David Shostac, flute; Jerry Kirkbride, clarinet; Edward Yadzinski, bass clarinet, William Lane, horn; Jon Hassell, trumpet; Edward Burnham, percussion; Niccolò Castiglioni, piano; Suzanne Thomas, harp; Charles Haupt, violin; David Rosenboom, viola; Makoto Michii, bass; Carlos Roqué Alsina, conductor
    Duration: 9:20
    Work number: ENM035-05
    Licht, Dorrit
    Sonnet thirty-five for two voices and violin (1961)
    Performers: Miriam Abramowitsch, soprano; Merete Bekkelund, mezzo-soprano; Charles Haupt, violin
    Duration: 6:27
  - Evenings for New Music Concert 37, February 10, 1968, 1 compact disc; Transferred from: Reel 47 Preservation copy on DVD 21 Performed at Albright-Knox Art Gallery (Box 1, Cd 30)
    Work number: ENM037-01
    Wilcox, A. Gordon
    A show of fourths (1966)
    Performers: Laurence Trott, flute; Lawrence Singer, oboe; Jerry Kirkbride, clarinet; Darlene Reynard, bassoon; William Lane, horn; Dowell Multer, piano; Charles Haupt, Egon Mayer, violins; David Rosenboom, viola; Bruce Cramer, violoncello; Makoto Michii, bass; Jan Williams, conductor
    Duration: 4:43
    Work number: ENM037-02
    Tropi (1959)
    Performers: Thomas Perazzoli, flute; Jerry Kirkbride, clarinet; Edward Burnham, percussion; Carlos Roqué Alsina, piano; Charles Haupt, violin; Robert Martin, violoncello; Melvin Strauss, conductor
    Duration: 8:10
    Work number: ENM037-03
    Dallapiccola, Luigi, 1904-1975
    Parole di San Paolo (1964)
    Performers: Miriam Abramowitsch, soprano; Thomas Perazzoli, flute; Laurence Trott, alto flute; Jerry Kirkbride, clarinet; Edward Yadzinski, bass clarinet; Edward Burnham, vibraphone and marimba; Margaret Krimsky-Hassell, celesta; Suzanne Thomas, harp; David Rosenboom, viola; Robert Martin, violoncello; Melvin Strauss, conductor
    Duration: 9:18
    Work number: ENM037-04
    Klavierstück XI (1956)
    Duration: 7:29
    Work number: ENM037-05
    Del Tredici, David
    I hear an army (1964)
    Performers: Miriam Abramowitsch, soprano; Donald Downs, Frank Preuss, violins; Jesse Levine, viola; Robert Martin, violoncello; David Del Tredici, conductor
    Duration: 10:11
    Work number: ENM037-06
    Caroms (1966)
    Performers: Thomas Perazzoli, flute; Jerry Kirkbride, clarinet; Jon Hassell, trumpet; Edward Burnham, Jan Williams, percussion; Carlos Roqué Alsina, Margaret Krimsky-Hassell, piano; Makoto Michii, bass; Melvin Strauss, conductor
    Duration: 6:03
  - Evenings for New Music Concert 39, March 3, 1968, 1 compact disc; Transferred from: Reel 48-Reel 49 Preservation copy on DVD 22 Performed at Albright-Knox Art Gallery (Box 1, Cd 31)
    Work number: ENM039-01
    Baird, Tadeusz, 1928-1981
    Etiuda (1961)
    Performers: Crane Collegiate Singers, SUNY College at Potsdam; Brock McElheran, conductor
    Work number: ENM039-02
    Somers, Harry, 1925-1999
    Crucifixion (1966)
    Performers: Crane Collegiate Singers, SUNY College at Potsdam; Lawrence Singer, English horn; Frank Collura, Jon Hassell, trumpets; David Ameele, Bailey, percussion; Brock McElheran, conductor
    Work number: ENM039-03
    McElheran, Brock
    Patterns in sound (1964). Scherzo
    Duration: 2:03
    Work number: ENM039-04
    Fragments of Archilochos (1965)
    Performers: Crane Collegiate Singers, SUNY College at Potsdam; Robert Betts, countertenor; Miriam Abramowitsch, Melvin Strauss, speakers; Edward Burnham, Lynn Harbold, Jan Williams, percussion; Oswald Rantucci, mandolin; Jonathan Marcus, guitar; Lukas Foss, conductor
    Duration: 10:30
    Work number: ENM039-05
    Non-improvisation (1967)
    Performers: Edward Yadzinski, clarinet and percussion; Lukas Foss, piano; Jan Williams, electronic organ; Robert Martin, violoncello
    Duration: 16:25
    Work number: ENM039-06
    A room-She is asleep (1943)
    Performers: Edward Burnham, Lynn Harbold, John Rowland, Jan Williams, percussion; John Cage, piano(?)
    Duration: 6:15
    Work number: ENM039-07
    To that predestined dancing place (1967)
    Performers: Edward Burnham, Lynn Harbold, John Rowland, Jan Williams, percussion
    Duration: 8:02
  - Evenings for New Music Concert 40, March 10, 1968, 1 compact disc; Transferred from: Reel 50-Reel 51 Preservation copy on DVD 23 Performed at Albright-Knox Art Gallery (Box 1, Cd 32)
    Work number: ENM040-01
    Sequenza V for trombone solo (1966)
    Performers: Stuart Dempster, trombone
    Work number: ENM040-02
    Herma; musique symbolique pour piano (1961)
    Performers: Yuji Takahashi, piano
    Duration: 7:34
    Work number: ENM040-03
    Takahashi, Yuji, 1938-
    Six elements (1965)
    Performers: Donald Downs, Charles Haupt, Frank Preuss, David Rosenboom, violins; Yuji Takahashi, conductor
    Duration: 5:26
    Work number: ENM040-04
    Bridges (1967)
    Performers: Jan Williams, percussion; Yuji Takahashi, electric piano; Robert Martin, violoncello
    Work number: ENM040-05
    Hassell, Jon, 1937-
    Blackboard piece with girls and loops (1967)
    Performers: Coni Burnham, Margaret Hassell, electronic blackboards
    Duration: 11:33
    Work number: ENM040-06
    Moran, Robert, 1937-
    Elegant journey with stopping points of interest (1965)
    Performers: Edward Burnham, percussion
    Duration: 16:58
    Work number: ENM040-07
    Auftrag 1967 (1967)
    Performers: Charles Wyatt, flute; Jerry Kirkbride, clarinet; Darlene Reynard, bassoon; William Lane, horn; Edward Burnham, percussion; Charles Haupt, violin; David Rosenboom, viola; Robert Martin, violoncello; Makoto Michii, bass; Carlos Roqué Alsina, conductor
    Duration: 9:39
  - Evenings for New Music Concert 41, March 17, 1968, 2 compact discs; Transferred from: Reel 52-Reel 54 Preservation copy on DVD 24 Performed at Albright-Knox Art Gallery (Box 1, Cd 33-34)
    Work number: ENM041-01
    Votre Faust (1967). Decors
    Performers: Miriam Abramowitsch, soprano; Merete Bekkelund, mezzo-soprano; Laurence Bogue, baritone; Robert Beckwith, bass-baritone; Charles Wyatt, flute; Jerry Kirkbride, clarinet; Edward Yadzinski, saxophone; Darlene Reynard, bassoon; William Lane, horn; Frank Collura, trumpet; Jan Williams, percussion; Yuji Takahashi, piano; Suzanne Thomas, harp; Frank Preuss, violin; Robert Martin, violoncello; Makoto Michii, bass; David Behrman, tape recorder; Joseph Romanowski, acoustical engineering; Henri Pousseur, conductor
    Duration: 47:24
    Work number: ENM041-02
    Votre Faust (1967). Miroir
    Performers: Marcelle Mercenier, piano
    Duration: 13:46
    Work number: ENM041-03
    Votre Faust (1967). Scenes
    Duration: 24:20
  - Evenings for New Music Concert 43, April 27, 1968, 1 compact disc; Transferred from: Reel 55-Reel 56 Preservation copy on DVD 25 Performed at Albright-Knox Art Gallery (Box 1, Cd 35)
    Work number: ENM043-01
    Mayer, Egon
    Piece for thirteen musicians (1967-68)
    Performers: David Shostac, flute; Lawrence Singer, oboe; Jerry Kirkbride, clarinet; Stephen Seiffert, horn; Jon Hassell, trumpet; Stuart Dempster, trombone; Charles Haupt, Gregory Krystaf, Egon Mayer, violins; David Rosenboom, viola; Robert Martin, violoncello; Makoto Michii, bass; Carlos Roqué Alsina, conductor
    Duration: 10:20
    Work number: ENM043-02
    Bornstein, Charles Zachary, 1951-
    Mélange for piano (1968)
    Duration: 14:06
    Work number: ENM043-03
    Duet for voice and prepared piano (1943)
    Performers: Merete Bekkelund, mezzo-soprano; Yuji Takahashi, prepared piano
    Duration: 7:03
    Work number: ENM043-04
    Accord (1966)
    Performers: Miriam Abramowitsch, soprano; David Shostac, flute; Stuart Dempster, trombone; Jan Williams, percussion; Yuji Takahashi, piano; Robert Martin, violoncello; Carlos Roqué Alsina, conductor
    Duration: 13:02
    Work number: ENM043-05
    Kolb, Barbara
    Three place settings (1967)
    Performers: Laurence Bogue, bass-baritone; Jerry Kirkbride, clarinet; Edward Burnham, percussion; Charles Haupt, violin; Makoto Michii, bass; Jan Williams, conductor
    Duration: 7:04
    Work number: ENM043-06
    Behrman, David
    Questions from the floor (1968)
    Performers: David Behrman, Stuart Dempster, Jon Hassel, Yuji Takahashi, electronicists
    Duration: 13:28
  - Evenings for New Music Lecture Concert 43a, April 27, 1968, 1 compact disc; Transferred from: Reel 57 Preservation copy on DVD 26 Recorded at very low volume. (Box 1, Cd 36-37)
    Program titled: New methods of computer composition and sound synthesis, a lecture by Lejaren Hiller. It is unclear how this was related to Evenings for New Music programming.
  - Evenings for New Music Concert 45, November 3, 1968, 1 compact disc; Transferred from: Reel 58-Reel 59 Preservation copy on DVD 27 Performed at Albright-Knox Art Gallery (Box 1, Cd 38)
    Work number: ENM045-01
    Nouvelles aventures (1962-65)
    Performers: Gwendolin Sims, Barbara Smith Conrad, sopranos; Laurence Bogue, baritone; Robert Cram, flute; William Lane, horn; Edward Burnham, percussion; Stephen Manes, piano; Yuji Takahashi, harpsichord; Marijke Verberne, violoncello; Tom Coleman, bass; Lukas Foss, conductor
    Duration: 11:08
    Work number: ENM045-02
    Paradigm (1968)
    Performers: Jerry Kirkbride, clarinet; Jan Williams, percussion; Jonathan Marcus, guitar; Charles Haupt, violin; Marijke Verberne, violoncello; Jon Hassell, Stanley Lunetta, Joseph Romanowski, electronicists; Jan Williams, conductor
    Duration: 21:37
    Work number: ENM045-03
    Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994
    An avalanche for pitchman, prima donna, player piano, percussionist and pre-recorded playback (1968)
    Performers: Joseph Glosson, reciter; Gwendolin Sims, soprano; Stanley Lunetta, percussion; Joseph Romanowski, Gerry Wykcoff, electronicists; Jonathan Marcus, actor (stage hand); Lejaren Hiller, conductor
    Duration: 11:40
  - Evenings for New Music Concert 46, December 15, 1968, 1 compact disc; Transferred from: Reel 60-Reel 61 Preservation copy on DVD 28 Performed at Albright-Knox Art Gallery (Box 1, Cd 39)
    Work number: ENM046-01
    Bartolozzi, Bruno
    Concertazioni per oboe e alcuni strumenti (1965)
    Performers: Lawrence Singer, oboe; Jan Williams, percussion; Jonathan Marcus, guitar; Jesse Levine, viola; Tom Coleman, bass
    Duration: 13:40
    Work number: ENM046-02
    Lunetta, Stanley
    Spider song (1968)
    Performers: Larry Austin, Stanley Lunetta, composers/performers; Jan Williams, guide; Jon Hassell, Joseph Romanowski, audio technicians; Charles Haupt, visual technician; Edward Burnham, Robert Cram, Jonathan Marcus, Sharon Lunetta, practitioners
    Duration: 3:45
    Work number: ENM046-03
    Eastman, Julius
    Piano piece I (1968)
    Performers: Julius Eastman, piano
    Duration: 0:54
    Work number: ENM046-04
    Piano piece II (1966)
    Duration: 2:51
    Work number: ENM046-05
    Piano piece III (1968)
    Duration: 0:40
    Work number: ENM046-06
    Piano piece IV (1968)
    Duration: 2:15
    Work number: ENM046-07
    Reynolds, Roger, 1934-
    Traces (1968)
    Performers: Robert Cram, flute; Yuji Takahashi, piano; Marijke Verberne, violoncello
    Duration: 20:12
    Work number: ENM046-08
    Subotnick, Morton
    The tarot (1965)
    Performers: Robert Cram, flute; Lawrence Singer, oboe; Jon Hassell, trumpet; James Kasprowicz, trombone; Edward Burnham, Stanley Lunetta, Jan Williams, Yuji Takahashi, percussion; Jesse Levine, viola; Tom Coleman, bass; Morton Subotnick, conductor
    Duration: 9:30
  - Evenings for New Music Concert 48, February 2, 1969, 1 compact disc; Transferred from: Reel 62-Reel 63 Preservation copy on DVD 29 Performed at Albright-Knox Art Gallery (Box 1, Cd 40)
    Work number: ENM048-01
    Applebaum, Edward
    Montages (1968)
    Performers: Jerry Kirkbride, clarinet; Stephen Manes, piano; Marijke Verberne, violoncello
    Duration: 9:05
    Work number: ENM048-02
    Berg, Alban, 1885-1935
    Vier Stücke für Klarinette und Klavier, op. 5 (1924)
    Performers: Jerry Kirkbride, clarinet; Stephen Manes, piano
    Duration: 7:25
    Work number: ENM048-03
    Evangelisti, Franco
    Proporzioni (1958)
    Performers: Robert Cram, flute
    Duration: 4:35
    Work number: ENM048-04
    Sechs Gesänge, op. 14 (1917-21)
    Performers: Gwendolin Sims, soprano; Jerry Kirkbride, clarinet; Edward Yadzinski, bass clarinet; Charles Haupt, violin; Marijke Verberne, violoncello; Jan Williams, conductor
    Duration: 8:05
    Work number: ENM048-05
    Rands, Bernard
    Espressione IV (1964)
    Performers: Julius Eastman, Yuji Takahashi, pianos
    Duration: 13:08
    Work number: ENM048-06
    Colgrass, Michael
    Light spirit (1963)
    Performers: Robert Cram, flute; Edward Burnham, Jan Williams, percussion; Jonathan Marcus, guitar; Jesse Levine, viola; Melvin Strauss, conductor
    Duration: 8:00
  - Evenings for New Music Concert 50, March 29, 1969, 2 compact discs; Transferred from: Reel 64 Preservation copy on DVD 30 Performed at Albright-Knox Art Gallery (Box 2, Cd 41-42)
    Work number: ENM050-01
    Bartók, Belá, 1881-1945
    Contrasts (1938)
    Performers: Jerry Kirkbride, clarinet; Stephen Manes, piano; Charles Haupt, violin
    Duration: 18:25
    Work number: ENM050-02
    Largo (1901)
    Work number: ENM050-03
    Fredrickson, Thomas, 1928-
    Trio (1968)
    Performers: Robert Cram, flute; Jan Williams, vibes; Tom Coleman, bass
    Duration: 9:50
    Work number: ENM050-04
    Górecki, Henryk Mikolaj, 1933-
    Concerto for five instruments and string quartet (1957)
    Performers: Robert Cram, flute; Jerry Kirkbride, clarinet; Jon Hassell, trumpet; Jan Williams, percussion; Oswald Rantucci, mandolin; Charles Haupt, Kenneth Fung, violins; Frank Riley, viola; Marijke Verberne, violoncello; Melvin Strauss, conductor
    Duration: 10:18
    Work number: ENM050-05
    Oliveira, Jocy de, 1936-
    Estoria (1967)
    Performers: Gwendolin Sims, soprano; Edward Burnham, percussion
    Work number: ENM050-06
    Prajna Paramita (1968)
    Performers: Gwendolin Sims, soprano; Robert Cram, flute; Jerry Kirkbride, clarinet; Jon Hassell, trumpet; Donald Miller, bass trombone; Edward Burnham, Jan Williams, percussion; Suzanne Thomas, harp; Charles Haupt, violin; Marijke Verberne, violoncello; Yuji Takahashi, conductor
    Duration: 16:15
  - Evenings for New Music Concert 52, May 3, 1969, 2 compact discs; Transferred from: Reel 65-Reel 66 Preservation copy on DVD 31 Performed at Albright-Knox Art Gallery (Box 2, Cd 43-44)
    Work number: ENM052-01
    8:30-9:37 P.M. 4 III 69 from "Map of 49's dream the two systems of eleven sets of galactic intervals"(1969)
    Performers: Marian Zazeela, amplified voice; La Monte Young, amplified voice and synthesizer
    Duration: 1:06:45
    Work number: ENM052-02
    Riley, Terry, 1935-
    Kundalini dervish (1969)
    Performers: Lawrence Singer, oboe; Terry Riley, soprano saxophone; Edward Burnham, Jan Williams, percussion; Yuji Takahashi, keyboard; Jon Hassell, electronicist
    Duration: 25:25
    Work number: ENM052-03